RG 183, Connecticut River Valley Flood Control Commission
Connecticut State Library
- Series 8. NENYIAC, 1952-1956
  - Fish and wildlife, 1954 (Box 14, Folder 49)
  - Flood control, 1954-1955 (Box 14, Folder 50)
  - General, 1952-1955 (Box 14, Folder 51)
  - Meeting minutes, 1953-1954 (Box 14, Folder 52)
  - Mineral resources, 1954 (Box 14, Folder 53)
  - Navigation and erosion, undated (Box 14, Folder 54)
  - Pollution, 1954 (Box 14, Folder 55)
  - Power study, 1955-1956 (Box 14, Folder 56)
  - Public health, 1954-1955 (Box 14, Folder 57)
  - Recreation, 1954-1955 (Box 14, Folder 58)
  - Sedimentation, 1954 (Box 14, Folder 59)
  - Sedimentation committee, 1954 (Box 14, Folder 60)
- Series 9. Photographs, circa 1936-1978
  - Dedication and Groundbreaking Ceremonies
    - Littleville Dam dedication, 1965 (Box 15, Folder 1-8)
    - Littleville Dam groundbreaking, 1962 (Box 15, Folder 9-33)
    - Otter Brook Dam dedication, 1958 (Box 15, Folder 34-46)
    - Otter Brook Dam groundbreaking, 1956 (Box 15, Folder 47-51)
  - Portraits (Box 15)
    - Beattie, Neal W., New Hampshire, undated (Box 15, Folder 52)
    - Kelly, Eugen T., Connecticut, undated (Box 15, Folder 53)
    - Parker, Alban J., Chairman, Vermont, undated (Box 15, Folder 54)
    - Shutler, Philip, Director, undated (Box 15, Folder 55)
    - Sterling, Clarence I., Jr., Massachusetts, undated (Box 15, Folder 56)
    - Thames, Arthur E., Connecticut, undated (Box 15, Folder 57)
    - Tufts, Nathan, Massachusetts, undated (Box 15, Folder 58)
    - White, Walter G., New Hampshire, undated (Box 15, Folder 59)
    - Vibart, Horace C., Connecticut, undated (Box 15, Folder 60)
    - Group portraits, circa 1978, undated (Box 15, Folder 61-64)
  - Floods
    - Connecticut (Box 17)
      - Collinsville, 1955 August 26; 5 photographs (Box 17, Folder 1)
      - Farmington, 1955 August 26 (Box 17, Folder 2)
      - Hartford, 1938 (Box 17, Folder 3)
      - Naugatuck, 1955 August 28 (Box 17, Folder 4)
      - New Hartford, 1955 August 21-26; 2 photographs (Box 17, Folder 5)
      - Norwalk, 1955 October 17 (Box 17, Folder 6)
      - Putnam, 1955 August 22; 3 photographs (Box 17, Folder 7)
      - Salmon Brook, 1955 August 21 (Box 17, Folder 8)
      - Simsbury, 1955 August 21; 3 photographs (Box 17, Folder 9)
      - Torrington, 1955 August 20-29; 12 photographs (Box 17, Folder 10)
      - Unionville, 1955 August 26 (Box 17, Folder 11)
      - Waterbury, 1955 August-September; 2 photographs (Box 17, Folder 12)
      - Winsted, 1955 August 21-16; 8 photographs (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Massachusetts (Box 17)
      - North Oxford, 1955 August 19 (Box 17, Folder 14)
      - Southbridge, 1955 August 22; 5 photographs (Box 17, Folder 15)
      - Westfield, 1955 August 20; 10 photographs (Box 17, Folder 16)
      - Worcester, 1955 August 19; 7 photographs (Box 17, Folder 17)
      - Woronoco, 1955 August 20 (Box 17, Folder 18)
    - New Hampshire (Box 16)
      - Keene, 1936 March, 1938, undated (Box 16, Folder 65-81)
    - Rhode Island (Box 17)
      - Blackstone River, Woonsocket and Manville, 1955 August 20-21; 5 photographs (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - Dams and Reservoirs (Box 17)
    - Connecticut (Box 17)
      - Colebrook Dam, 1969; 6 photographs (Box 17, Folder 19)
      - Mad River Dam, undated; 2 photographs (Box 17, Folder 20)
    - Massachusetts (Box 17)
      - Barre Falls Dam, 1956-1958; 6 photographs (Box 17, Folder 22)
      - Birch Hill Reservoir Recreation Area, 1962, undated; 2 photographs (Box 17, Folder 23)
      - Conant Brook Dam, undated; 3 photographs (Box 17, Folder 24)
      - Knightville Dam and Reservoir, 1955, undated; 4 photographs (Box 17, Folder 25)
      - Littleville Dam, 1963, 1968, undated; 12 photographs (Box 17, Folder 26)
      - Tully Dam, 1957-1960, undated; 9 photographs (Box 17, Folder 27)
    - New Hampshire (Box 17)
      - Otter Brook Dam, 1955-1958, undated; 6 photographs (Box 17, Folder 28)
      - Otter Brook Dam Reservoir Recreation Area, 1961-1962, undated; 4 photographs (Box 17, Folder 29)
      - Otter Brook State Park, 1961, undated; 3 photographs (Box 17, Folder 30)
      - Surry Mountain Dam, circa 1951-1961; 3 photographs (Box 17, Folder 31)
    - Vermont (Box 17)
      - Ball Mountain Dam, 1957-1977, undated; 18 photographs (Box 17, Folder 32)
      - North Hartland Dam, 1960, undated; 10 photographs (Box 17, Folder 33)
      - North Hartland Dam Recreation Area, 1963 August 24 (Box 17, Folder 34)
      - North Hartland Reservoir Quechee Gorge, 1956, undated; 6 photographs (Box 17, Folder 35)
      - North Hartland Reservoir Quechee Gorge camp area, undated; 4 photographs (Box 17, Folder 36)
      - North Springfield Dam, circa 1958, 1960, undated; 8 photographs (Box 17, Folder 37)
      - North Springfield Dam North Branch Recreation Pool, 1960 October 8; 2 photographs (Box 17, Folder 38)
      - Townshend Dam, 1961, undated; 5 photographs (Box 17, Folder 39)
      - Townshend Reservoir Recreation Area, undated; 9 photographs (Box 17, Folder 40)
      - Union Village Dam, 1950-1957; 6 photographs (Box 17, Folder 41)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 17)
    - Annual reports - negatives of maps, 1969-1970; 1 photograph, 11 negatives (Box Drawer 84, Folder Item 3)
    - Connecticut River, undated (Box 17, Folder 42)
    - Dams and Reservoirs, undated; 3 photographs (Box 17, Folder 43)
    - Floods, undated; 4 photographs (Box 17, Folder 44)
    - Group portraits, undated; 5 photographs (Box 17, Folder 45)
    - Publications, undated; 8 items (Box 17, Folder 46)
    - West River Sand and Gravel, Inc., undated; 10 photographs (Box 17, Folder 47)
    - Photograph album, circa 1936-1970; 1 album (20 photographs) (Box 18)
      Contents: Connecticut River Basin Flood Control Projects map; Knightville Dam; Littleville Dam; Birch Hill Dam; Tully Lake; Barre Falls Dam; Otter Brook Lake; Surrey Mountain Lake; Union Village Dam; North Hartland Lake; North Springfield Lake; Townshend Lake; Ball Mountain Lake; Chicopee Local Protection; Colebrook Lake; Conant Brook Dam; East Hartford Local Protection; Mad River Dam; Sucker Brook Dam; Hartford Local Protection.
    - West River, Vermont, 1938 October (Box 18)
- Series 10. Maps, 1942-1966
  - Connecticut River Flood Control Birch Hill Reservoir Area Land Acquisition, Millers River, Massachusetts, 1942 January 25; 2 maps; Prepared by War Department, Corps of Engineers, U.S. Army, U.S. Engineer Office, Providence, Rhode Island. (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Connecticut River Flood Control, Chicopee River Basin, Conant Brook Dam Reservoir Map, Chicopee River, Massachusetts, 1959 August; 1 map; Prepared by U.S. Army Engineer Division, New England, Corps of Engineers, Waltham, Massachusetts.; 1 inch = 500 feet (Box 21, Folder 2)
    Drawing No. CT-1-5602
    Plate No. 4
    Sheet 1 of 1
    To accompany report dated 8 September 1959
  - Real Estate Conant Brook Dam & Reservoir, 1964 July; 4 maps; Prepared by Department of the Army, Office of the Division Engineer, New England Division.; 1 inch = 200 feet (Box 21, Folder 2)
    Segments '1'-'4'
    Drawing Numbers 1732-1735
  - Connecticut River Basin Farmington River Watershed Dam and Reservoir Sites Under Study, Farmington River, Connecticut, 1956 June; 2 duplicate maps; Prepared by Corps of Engineers, U.S. Army, Office of the Division Engineer, New England Division, Boston, Massachusetts. (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Connecticut River Basin Farmington River Watershed Dam and Reservoir Sites Under Study, Farmington River, Connecticut, 1957 December; 1 map; Prepared by Corps of Engineers, U.S. Army, Office of the Division Engineer, New England Division, Boston, Massachusetts. (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Connecticut River Flood Control Gaysville Dam Reservoir Map, White River, Vermont, 1966 October; 2 maps; Prepared by Department of the Army, New England Division, Corps of Engineers, Waltham, Massachusetts. (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Preliminary Report Gaysville Reservoir Flood Control Plan Recreation Pool at EL. 680 with Subimpoundments, 1963 June; 2 maps; Prepared by Anderson-Nichols consulting engineers, Boston, Massachusetts. (Box 21, Folder 4)
    Plate 1 and 2
  - Preliminary Report Gaysville Reservoir Flood Control Plan Recreation Pool at EL. 720, 1963 June; 2 maps; Prepared by Anderson-Nichols consulting engineers, Boston, Massachusetts. (Box 21, Folder 4)
    Plate 3 and 4
  - Preliminary Report Gaysville Reservoir Flood Control Plan Recreation Pool at EL. 735, 1963 June; 2 maps; Prepared by Anderson-Nichols consulting engineers, Boston, Massachusetts. (Box 21, Folder 4)
    Plate 5 and 6
  - Preliminary Report Gaysville Reservoir Recreation Pool at EL. 771, 1963 June; 2 maps; Prepared by Anderson-Nichols consulting engineers, Boston, Massachusetts. (Box 21, Folder 4)
    Plate 7 and 8
  - North Hartland Reservoir. Land Map of A.G. Dewey Co., undated; 1 map; 1 inch = 500 feet (Box 21, Folder 5)
    Map of property...prior to April 1, 1958
  - Preliminary Connecticut River Flood Control North Hartland Dam Reservoir Map, Ottauquechee River, Vermont, 1946 January; 1 map; Prepared by War Department, Corps of Engineers, U.S. Army, U.S. Engineer Office, Providence, Rhode Island.; 1 inch = 800 feet (Box 21, Folder 5)
    File No. CT-1-1912
  - Connecticut River Basin North Springfield Dam Reservoir Map, 1954 October; 2 maps; Prepared by New England-New York Inter-Agency Committee. (Box 21, Folder 6)
    Plate No. 58 and 59
  - North Springfield Flood Control Dam and Black River Watershed topographical map, undated; 1 map (Box 21, Folder 6)
    Map consists of several parts of USGS topographical survey maps
  - Real Estate North Springfield Reservoir, 1957 April; 2 duplicate maps; Prepared by Department of the Army, Office of the Division Engineer, New England Division. (Box 21, Folder 6)
    Drawing No. NED-PA-1368
  - Vermont Highway District No. 4, Windsor County, circa 1959; 1 map (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Connecticut River Flood Control North Springfield Dam and Reservoir Project Location & Vicinity Map, Black River, Vermont, 1958 February; 1 map; Prepared by Corps of Engineers, U.S. Army, Office of the District Engineer, Omaha District, Omaha, Nebraska. (Box 21, Folder 6)
    Sheet 2 of 134
    Drawing Number CT-1-5021
  - Connecticut River Basin Photogrammetric Topographic Survey North Springfield Damsite and Reservoir Area, Black River, Vermont, 1956 August; 4 maps; Prepared by Maps, Incorporated air survey contractors, Harbor Field, Baltimore, Maryland.; 1 inch = 500 feet (Box 21, Folder 6)
    Drawing Numbers CT-5-1636 to CT-5-1639
  - Connecticut River Flood Control North Springfield Dam and Reservoir Relocations-Highways & Cemetery, Black River, Vermont, 1958 January; 1 map; Prepared by Corps of Engineers, U.S. Army, Office of the Division Engineer, New England Division, Boston, Massachusetts.; 1 inch = 1000 feet (Box 21, Folder 6)
    Drawing Number CT-1-4449
  - Connecticut River Flood Control Otter Brook Dam and Reservoir Map, Otter Brook, Ashuelot River, New Hampshire, 1947 February; 1 map; Prepared by War Department, Corps of Engineers, U.S. Army, New England Division, Boston, Massachusetts.; 1 inch = 500 feet (Box 21, Folder 7)
    File No. CT-1-2117
    Plate No. 18
  - Real Estate Otter Brook Dam and Reservoir, 1956 April; 4 duplicate maps; Prepared by Department of the Army, Office of the Division Engineer, New England Division.; 1/8 inch = 1 foot (Box 21, Folder 7)
    Drawing No. NED-PA-1294
  - Connecticut River Flood Control Surry Mountain Dam Reservoir Map, Ashuelot River, New Hampshire, 1947 February; 1 map; Prepared by War Department, Corps of Engineers, U.S. Army, New England Division, Boston, Massachusetts.; 1 inch = 600 feet (Box 21, Folder 8)
    Sheet No. 1
    File No. CT.-1-2135
    Plate No. 17
  - Real Estate Surry Mountain Reservoir, 1952 March; 1 map; Prepared by Department of the Army, Office of the Division Engineer, New England Division. (Box 21, Folder 8)
    Drawing No. NED-PA 889
    Office, Chief of Engineers, Washington, D.C., Audited, Installation or Project No. C-696
  - Real Estate Townshend Reservoir, 1960 May; 2 maps; Prepared by Department of the Army, Office of the Division Engineer, New England Division. (Box 21, Folder 9)
    Segments "A" and "B"
    Drawing No. NED-PA-1411
  - Preliminary Connecticut River Flood Control Aerial Survey Record Townshend Reservoir, West River, Vermont, 1945 December; 1 map; Prepared by War Department, Corps of Engineers, U.S. Army, U.S. Engineer Office, Providence, Rhode Island.; 1 inch = 500 feet (Box 21, Folder 9)
    File No. CT-5-1573
    Printed May 20, 1946
  - Real Estate Ball Mountain Reservoir, 1957 January; 1 map; Prepared by Department of the Army, Office of the Division Engineer, New England Division. (Box 21, Folder 9)
    Segment "A"
    Sheet 2 of 2
    Drawing No. NED PA-870
  - Real Estate Townshend Reservoir, 1957 January; 2 maps; Prepared by Department of the Army, Office of the Division Engineer, New England Division. (Box 21, Folder 9)
    Segments "A"
  - Flood Control Dams in the Connecticut River Drainage Basin, undated; 1 map (Box 18)
  - Subject Files
    - Preliminary Connecticut River Flood Control Ball Mountain Dam Reservoir Map, West River, Vermont, 1946 May; 1 map; Prepared by War Department, Corps of Engineers, U.S. Army, U.S. Engineer Office, Providence, Rhode Island.; 1 inch = 1000 feet (Box 21, Folder 10)
      Map removed from Box 8, Folder 15
    - Real Estate Ball Mountain Reservoir, 1957 January; 1 map; Prepared by Department of the Army, Office of the Division Engineer, New England Division. (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Real Estate Barre Falls Dam and Reservoir, 1956 March; 1 map; Prepared by Department of the Army, Office of the Division Engineer, New England Division. (Box 21, Folder 11)
      Drawing No. NED-PA-1289
      Map removed from Box 8, Folder 18
    - Connecticut River Flood Control Barre Falls Dam Reservoir Map, Ware River, Massachusetts, 1946 August; 1 map; Prepared by War Department, Corps of Engineers, U.S. Army, U.S. Engineer Office, Providence, Rhode Island.; 1 inch = 1000 feet (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - Connecticut River Flood Control Chicopee River Basin Watershed Map, Chicopee River, Massachusetts, 1958 April; 1 map; Prepared by Corps of Engineers, U.S. Army, Office of the Division Engineer, New England Division, Boston, Massachusetts. (Box 21, Folder 12)
      Drawing No. CT-1-4436
      Map removed from Box 8, Folder 25
    - Preliminary Connecticut River Flood Control Conant Brook Dam Reservoir Map, Chicopee River, Massachusetts, 1959 April; 1 map; Prepared by Corps of Engineers, U.S. Army, Office of the Division Engineer, New England Division, Waltham, Massachusetts.; 1 inch = 500 feet (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - Monson, Massachusetts topographical map, 1955; 1 map; Prepared by Army Map Service, Corps of Engineers, U.S. Army, Washington, D.C.; 1:25,000 (Box 21, Folder 12)
      Sheet 6568 III SE Series V814
      Original map compiled by U.S. Geological Survey
      Map is marked with location of Conant Brook Damsite
- Series 11. Publications, 1927-1980
  - A Uniform Technique for Determining Flood Flow Frequencies. Washington, D.C.: Water Resources Council, 1967 December (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Barre Falls Dam Dedication Supplement of The Barre Gazette, 1958 May 15 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Colebrook River Dam and Reservoir dedication program, 1969 June 27 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - US War Department, Corps of Engineers, New England Division., 1947 March (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - US Army, Corps of Engineers, New England Division. Connecticut River Basin, Information on the scope and status of the civil works program of the Corps of Engineers in the Connecticut River Basin, 1956 September (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Connecticut River Valley newsletter and pamphlets, 1969-1970, undated (Box 19, Folder 14)
    Includes the following newsletter and pamphlets: Comprehensive Water and Related Land Resources Investigation, Connecticut River Basin; Connecticut River Watershed Council; The Happy Valley; Ground-Water Ecology and The Lower Connecticut River Basin; and Franklin Conservation District Newsletter.
  - Daily and Hourly Precipitation Supplement Storm of July 17-18, 1942, New York-Pennsylvania, U.S. Department of Commerce Weather Bureau in Cooperation with War Department Corps of Engineers and U.S. Department of Agriculture Office of Land Use Coordination - Flood Control. Albany, New York: Weather Bureau Office Hydrologic Unit, circa 1942-1943 (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - Sharp, A.L., A.E. Gibbs, and W.J. Owen. Development of a Procedure Estimating the Effects of Land and Watershed Treatment on Streamflow, Technical Bulletin No. 1352. Washington, D.C.: U.S. Government Printing Office, 1966 March (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - Vermont State Water Conservation Board. Effects of the "Comprehensive Plan for Flood Control of the Connecticut River", 1947 February (Box 19, Folder 17)
  - Fifty Pages of Excerpts from the Flood Control Hearings Before A Subcommittee of the Committee on Commerce, United State Senate, Seventy-Eighth Congress, Second Session, on H.R. 4485, An Act Authorizing the Construction of Certain Public Works on Rivers and Harbors for Flood Control and Other Purposes. Reproduced and Distributed by the National Reclamation Association, 1944 May-June (Box 19, Folder 18)
  - Mangan, John W. The Flood of July 1942 in the Upper Allegheny River and Sinnemahoning Creek Basins. Harrisburg, PA: Commonwealth of Pennsylvania Department of Forests and Waters, 1943 (Box 19, Folder 19)
  - Flood Water Flow, circa 1940-1980 (Box 19, Folder 20)
  - 50th Anniversary Knightville Dam program, 1991 August 10 (Box 19, Folder 21)
  - Miscellaneous, 1965 (Box 19, Folder 22)
  - US Army, Corps of Engineers, New England Division, Office of the Division Engineer. New England Floods of 1955, Part 2 Flood Discharges and Part 3 Flood Profiles, 1956 April (Box 19, Folder 23)
  - North Hartland Dam and Reservoir dedication program, 1961 August 4 (Box 19, Folder 24)
  - Atwood, R.E. Stories and Pictures of the Vermont Flood, November, 1927 (Box 19, Folder 25)
  - To Amend the Water Resources Planning Act. Hearing Before the Subcommittee on Energy Research and Water Resources of the Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs, United States Senate, Ninety-Fourth Congress, First Session, on S. 506..., S. 1299..., and S. 1596... Washington, D.C.: U.S. Government Printing Office, 1975 July 10 (Box 19, Folder 26)
  - Cunningham, Floyd F. 1001 Questions Answered About Water Resources. New York: Dodd, Mead & Company, 1967; 1 book (Box 20)
  - Peterson, Elmer. New York: The Devin-Adair Company, 1954; 1 book (Box 20)
  - The League of Women Voters Education Fund. Brattleboro, VT: The Stephen Greene Press, 1966; 1 book (Box 20)
  - Loery, Gordon, John O.C. McCrillis, Robert Williams, Jack Marmaras, and Philip W. Swift. The Connecticut River Watershed Council, Inc., 1953; 1 book (Box 20)
  - Hoyt, William G., and Walter B. Langbein. Princeton, NJ: Princeton University Press, 1955; 1 book (Box 20)
  - King, Thomson. Water: Miracle of Nature. New York: The Macmillan Company, 1953; 1 book (Box 20)
  - Agency of Environmental Conservation, State of Vermont, and Technical Services, New England River Basins Commission. Water and Related Land Resources Guide Plan Report Vermont Inventory and Analysis, 1974 June; 1 oversize volume (Box Drawer 84, Folder Item 4)
  - Frank, Bernard, and Anthony Netboy. Water, Land, and People. New York: Alfred A. Knopf, 1951; 1 book (Box 20)
  - Eckstein, Otto. Water Resource Development: The Economics of Project Evaluation. Cambridge, MA: Harvard University Press, 1965; 1 book (Box 20)
- Series 12. Accruals, 1953-2011
  - 2015-021, 1.25 cubic feet
    - Newsletters, meeting minutes, and financial records, 1967-2011; 22 folders (Box 1)
    - Financial reports, 1953-1981 (Box 2)
    - Tax losses and repayments, 1963-2011 (Box 2)
    - Timber resources, 1974-1975 (Box 2)